Paul Kröner

Software Engineer

paul.kroener@rplsoft.de

Currently

Freelance Software Engineer, living in Germany, 71522 Backnang (near Stuttgart).

Introduction

Hello, my name is Paul, born in 1984. I am a passionate Software Engineer. In the last years my main focus was with .NET / ASP.NET, developing web applications and APIs. Part of this were always different databases (including MSSQL, SQLite, Oracle) and front ends (including TypeScript/JavaScript, ASP.NET, WinForms, KnockoutJS). Regarding .NET libraries, I have a lot of experience with AutoMapper, Autofac and NHibernate.

Clean and maintained code, automated tests and documentation are a normal part of my work. I like to organize my work in a issue tracking system. A version control system to manage code and documents forms the basis.

I don't shy away from any challenge and am looking forward to interesting projects, new technologies and doing great work together.

Interests / Hobbies

Bicycle, traveling, cooking, baking, gardening

Work experience

01.2020 - 12.2022

Software development (part time)

Developing a web based software to automate creation and analysis of written exams

(Python, Django, ReactJS, SQLite, Docker)

12.2015 - 12.2022

Software Developer - L-mobile solutions GmbH & Co. KG, Sulzbach an der Murr

2020-2022

Developing an interface between ERP and a Field Service Management Software / CRM via OData API to replicate (import / export) data ERPs including proALPHA, InforCOM, SAP Business One (C#, SQLite, MSSQL, Oracle, HANA)

2018-2022

Developing a OData REST API for a Field Service Management Software / CRM (C#, ASP.NET, WebAPI)

2016-2022

Maintenance and feature development of a Field Service Management Software / CRM (C#, ASP.NET, JavaScript, MSSQL)

2016-2022

Maintenance and feature development of a planning tool for planning technician appointments (C#, VB.NET, WinForms, MSSQL)

2015-2016

Conception, development of customizations and support / maintenance of customer projects (C#, JavaScript, MSSQL)

10.2011 - 11.2015

Software Developer - iSILOG GmbH, later EDAG Production Solutions GmbH & Co. KG, Baden-Baden

2013-2015

Developing a web based solution for planning, simulating and analyzing value streams

(Java, JavaScript, Vaadin, PostgreSQL)

2012-2015

Developing an application for static capacity planning based on SAP production data

(C#, MSSQL)

2011-2015

Developing a plugin for Systems Navigator® Scenario Navigator for planning support by means of value stream analysis and simulation (C#, MSSQL)

2011-2015

Developing an interface between CAD system Siemens NX and Siemens SIMIT for the virtual commissioning within NX (C#)

2012-2014

Developing a web based project reporting solution based on data from Projektron BCS project management software (Java, C#, Vaadin, MSSQL)

- Customer and project support
- Simulation projects with Plant Simulation
- Administration IT infrastructure

10.2008 - 10.2011

Dual studies

- Simulation projects, new and further development of module libraries for Siemens Plant Simulation (material flow simulation)
- Development of libraries, plugins, support of customer projects for Xcelgo Experior (virtual commissioning)

Education

10.2008 - 10.2011

DHBW Karlsruhe

Study course

Applied computer science, specialization: software development

Bachelor thesis

"Durchgängige Simulation und virtuelle Inbetriebnahme komplexer Materialflusssysteme" ("Consistent simulation and virtual commissioning of complex material flow systems")

(Note: 1,3)

Abschluss

Bachelor of Science (B.Sc.)

(Note: 1,8)

04.2008 - 10.2008

Praktikum in Firma iSILOG GmbH, Bühl

Entwicklung einer Offline-Schnittstelle zwischen Plant Simulation und Cinema4D zur automatischen Animationserstellung auf Basis von Simulationsdaten

10.2003 - 04.2008	Technische Universität Ilmenau
	Informatik, Nebenfach: Automatisierungstechnik
09.1995 - 06.2003	Gymnasium Klosterschule Roßleben
	Abitur / Allgemeine Hochschulreife (Note: 2,6)
10.2000 - 06.2001	Van Wert High School
	Austauschschüler in Van Wert, OH (USA)